Download this resume: https://amazingandyyy.com/resume/

Andy Chen

Rich full product life-cycle engineer/design experience. Initial product with production-ready codes and helping many others. I believe the philosophy of "learning by doing" and "the best way to learn is to teach." amazingandyyy@gmail.com (408) 431-3552 (CA Time) github.com/amazingandyyy linkedin.com/in/amazingandyyy/

EXPERIENCE

<u>Vechain Community</u>, Open Source— Founder and Project *lead* May 2018 - PRESENT

- Contributed to vechain/thor, vechain/thorify, and other Vechain open source projects on GitHub.
- Initiative multiples demos about DApp, integrated with hyperledger, dockernized-DevOps for the dev. community, for the open source community
- Plan to initiate a Vechain Node Observation app and Vechain Full Node hosting service to the community.

<u>Ventured International Inc.</u>, San Francisco — *Chief Product* Officer July 2017 - April 2018 (Failed)

- Implemented TDD with Jest to engineer production-ready smart contracts in Solidity and deployed to Ethereum Live Network with Truffle framework.
- Launched VentureCoin(<u>VCN</u>), implement ERC20 token and a 3-month crowdsale on Nov.
- Launched the company website, whitepaper and branding designs. A reference to my article on how we build our product (here).

<u>Yeah Education Group</u>, Berkeley — Chief Technical Officer

Dec. 2015 - April 2017 (currently 3M A.R.)

- Led a software development team to iterate four versions of the full software architect and application in MERN stack, and built over 50 internal/external endpoints.
- The software solution successfully scaled the business 20 times to a 1M annual revenue (2016) and led into Berkeley Skydeck incubator cohort in April, 2017.

<u>Andysign Studio</u>, Mountain View — Software Developer

Oct 2014 - Sept. 2016

- Constructed freelancing website and branding design service.
 Launched 8 websites including Groove Trend and Swallet visited by 10K visitors daily.
- Implemented A/B testing for UI elements, heatmap analysis on user behaviors and website SEO leading to a 100% increase in traffic in the initial month.

TEACHING/MENTORSHIP

NodeSchool Oakland and San Francisco Chapter Served as regular monthly mentor in Nodeschool Oakland

Reactathon, 2017 Served as a mentor at the hackathon held by the Real World React organization

Active Medium Contributor
Developed and share a series
of tutorials on web
development,
blockchain-related smart
contract, DevOps and
software design topics

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTION

nodejs/node, submitted
PR#10092[merged] and
#10093[merged] to update
and improve testing
environment

dawsbot/mailto, submitted PR#3[Closed], PR#4[merged] to resolve multiple issues and optimize key features

ConsenSys/Token-Factory, submitted PR#54[Opend] to update error handling

Vechain/thorify, update documentation and propose new thorify features

EDUCATION

Draper University, San Mateo — Hero Training Program, top 3

Sept 2018 - Oct 2018

Completed Hero Training Program for 5 weeks, graduated at top 3 in the class, nominated as "the most positive student" by Tim Draper

University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley — Bachelor's of Science, Cognitive Science

June 2016 - July 2018

Courses: Data Visualization, Blockchain for Developers, Computer Human Interface, Cognitive Science, Linguistics, Data Structure, Discrete Math.

Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China — *Dropped out, Economics and Finance*

Aug 2012 - June 2014

Dropped out from SJTU Antai College of Economics & Management in 2014 then decided to go to California to pursue the American Dream.

PROJECTS

<u>Leptin</u> — A PoW cryptocurrency implement in Nodejs

Designed and Built a whole cryptocurrency in nodejs with leveraging the power of WebRTC, LevelDB, hyperlogs to build a peer-to-peer blockchain implementing Proof-of-work, secp256k1 and dynamical difficulty.

<u>Etherbrite</u> — An eventbrite-like DApp.

Built a DApp in Solidity, TruffleJS, Web3js and React/Redux. From deploying events on smart contract to register user and check user in.

VRPlayer — A video player built with ReactVR and openGL

Built this video player on the fist of ReactVR's launch, with a focus on the interaction details of user experience in virtual reality.

<u>Serperpay</u> — A fintech app to streamline the multiple-installments payment process.

A consumer and business-facing web app that integrated with Stripe payment API and CronJob to make monthly payment easy and flexible. Deployed to EC2 and pitched at the 2016 Plug&Play Fintech Demo Day.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End: HTML/SCSS/JS, React, Angular, Webpack, proficient in RWD

Fullstack: MEAN, MEAN 2.0, MERN, ROR

Backend: Golang, python

DevOps: Docker, TravisCI, AWS(VPC, EC2, S3), GCP, IBM Bluemix(hyperledger)

HACKATHONS/AWARDS

H4YT Hackathon 2018 - Top 3 nomination by Cosmos for building <u>Celadon</u>, a lotionjs middleware donating money to help our environment.

LAUNCH Hackathon 2016 - 1st place of Uber Challenge [2016] for building Teleport, an advertisement site that magically delivers customers to your door.

AT&T Mobile App Hackathon
- 1st Coding House Challenge
[2016] for building Masty, a
livestream app as
simultaneously a trading
marketplace for streamers.

AT&T IoT Hackathon - Best Mobile App and IoT Solution Overall[2015] for building Connect, a radio player controlled by a gesture controller, Myo.